<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on Padgett: Beyond-STAT</title>
    <link>/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on Padgett: Beyond-STAT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducing Lavaan from (almost) Scratch</title>
      <link>/tutorial/2019-10-27-lavaan-cfa-reproduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/2019-10-27-lavaan-cfa-reproduction/</guid>
      <description>Purpose:
To reproduce the maximum likelihood estimates from lavaan.To try, I will be using the HolzingerSwineford1939 dataset that comes with lavaan.These data form a three factor model with 9 items.
lavaan Resultsset.seed(2)library(lavaan)## Warning: package &amp;#39;lavaan&amp;#39; was built under R version 3.6.1## This is lavaan 0.6-5## lavaan is BETA software! Please report any bugs.HS.model &amp;lt;- &amp;#39; visual =~ x1 + x2 + x3textual =~ x4 + x5 + x6speed =~ x7 + x8 + x9 &amp;#39;fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stumbling with RStan</title>
      <link>/tutorial/2019-06-06-rstan-humble/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/2019-06-06-rstan-humble/</guid>
      <description>So I was listing to one of my favorite podcasts (DataFramed) a few months ago and a particularly interest guest was on talking.The guest was Michael Betancourt.
Reading about the REALLY cool HMCHMC is the shorthand for Hamiltonian Monte Carlo.
Trouble Getting StartedThe Getting Started page (‘https://github.com/stan-dev/rstan/wiki/RStan-Getting-Started’) is extremely thorough and gives some excellent pointerr.The page boils down to using the following R commands to get started</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Data from Regression Models</title>
      <link>/tutorial/2019-04-21-r-reg-sim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/2019-04-21-r-reg-sim/</guid>
      <description>This file extends the introduction I gave to simulating data from coin flips. Now, the goal is to show how the basics extend and can easily be used for helpful parts of study design planning.
Simulating More Complex Models We can easily extend the basic concepts of simulating from a simple population to simulating data from a more complex data structure. This is how we can simulate a simple regression model with one outcome (Y) and five predictors (x1, x2, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R and Simulating Data</title>
      <link>/tutorial/2018-12-10-r-simple-sim.rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/2018-12-10-r-simple-sim.rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>Before we get started with an introduction to simulation, we need to make sure that R and R Studio are downloaded on your computers.R is an open source and free statistical programming language.R utilizes user built ‘packages.’The package library is huge and you can find a package that does nearly anything you need it to and a large number of these are regularly updated.We will talk about packages a lot over the never few years so this is kind of tertiary.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>