<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Padgett: Beyond-STAT</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Padgett: Beyond-STAT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Write</title>
      <link>/post/why-i-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/why-i-write/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I have begun writing more and more. After a beer (or a few more than a beer) I was wondering how I ended up writing so much. Until I entered my current position as a PhD student I never thought writing would be a major aspect of my work. By work, I mean that I am researcher. My training is in educational measurement and advanced statistical methodology. A lot of what I consider my research is banging my head against a wall to get the darn computer software to quit returning errors during an analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting Growth Mixture Models</title>
      <link>/post/2018-12-17-gmm-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-12-17-gmm-reporting/</guid>
      <description>I am currently wrapping up my work on a project investigating the alcoholic tendencies of adolesences. The data come from a data study in the United Kingdom, and I was brought on the project to help with the analysis. For this study, the aim was to investigate the presence of unobserved heterogeneity on the growth trajectories of this construct of &amp;lsquo;alcoholic tendencies.&amp;rsquo; For this analysis, I implemented a Growth Mixture Model (GMM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting up Beyond-STAT</title>
      <link>/post/2018-12-07-hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-12-07-hello/</guid>
      <description>Hello people (or non-people, I aim to be inclusive)!
My name is Noah, and this is the start of my website and tutorial center! I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering why I should create a wedbsite and the ebst reason I ahve come up with is to have a single place to store many of my ideas and struggles (with R in particular). The name I came up with Beyond-STAT is mean to sum up my work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Academic makes it easy to create a beautiful website for free using Markdown. Customize anything on your site with widgets, themes, and language packs.
Follow our easy step by step guide to learn how to build your own free website with Academic. Check out the personal demo or the business demo of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes.
 View the documentation Ask a question Request a feature or report a bug Updating?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>